<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Pithy Branding-Friendly Name for a Website Goes Here]]></title>
  <link href="http://thejimnicholson.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thejimnicholson.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-12T11:00:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://thejimnicholson.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jim Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deploying OpenVPN Part 1: why?]]></title>
    <link href="http://thejimnicholson.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/deploying-openvpn/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T13:29:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://thejimnicholson.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/deploying-openvpn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After years of working inside a &ldquo;walled garden,&rdquo; where I had limited access to clients and limited ability to work remotely, I&rsquo;m now a consultant working mostly on short-term projects. Some of those projects are done remotely, while others require me to be at a customer&rsquo;s location. Meanwhile, the team I&rsquo;m working with are distributed around the globe, and our &ldquo;infrastructre&rdquo; consists mostly of SaaS cloud sites and a mix of equipment sitting in various people&rsquo;s bedrooms, home offices and basements (including mine.)</p>

<p>As near as I can determine, my remote access requirements are:</p>

<ul>
<li>I need to access systems that are on my home network remotely.</li>
<li>I need to access systems that are on the team&rsquo;s network.</li>
<li>I need to be able to give other team members access to systems on my network.</li>
</ul>


<p>Additionally, I&rsquo;d like to host the infrastructure to support this using virtual machines, because that&rsquo;s how I roll.</p>

<p>One possible solution would be to run Mac OS X Server to host the VPN connections. This makes sense because my house is almost exclusively a Mac house these days, except for my occasional (and usually work-related) Linux use. The snag is that while I have some &ldquo;spare&rdquo; Mac hardware that can run OS X Server, none can be upgraded to Mavericks.</p>

<p>So the solution I&rsquo;m pursuing is to build out my home office infrastructure using Linux, following roughly this approach:</p>

<ul>
<li>Build a hypervisor to run my virtual machines</li>
<li>Install some implementation of OpenVPN on a virtual machine, preferably using a virtual appliance.</li>
<li>Configure my Airport Extreme to route VPN traffic from the internet into my OpenVPN host</li>
<li>Set up access so I can get onto my home network when I&rsquo;m not at home, via my various devices.</li>
<li>Connect my home network into the office network.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ll be posting more as things progress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started]]></title>
    <link href="http://thejimnicholson.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/getting-started/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T11:37:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://thejimnicholson.github.io/blog/2014/02/10/getting-started</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another new blog? Yep, despite my reservations, I&rsquo;m determined to try this out. Actually, static site generation makes a great deal of sense considering the way blogs get hijacked these days.</p>

<p>Anyway, the first topic I&rsquo;m going to address (in my typical ADHD fashion) is VPN access. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
